Hello and welcome back to the course on deep natural
language processing. And today we're going to talk about
the types of natural language processing. So we've got
two men diagrams here or we got a band diagram
of two circles in it, and we're going to
look at the different areas off natural language processing that
are going to come up in this course. So
on the letter got natural language processing overall on DH
. This refers to the whole circle on the left
. So the reason why we've called in just this
green part is because that's the non overlapping part.
So we know that anything in here eyes just national
language processing without with disregard to this second circle.
But natural language processing is indeed everything that is in
this first circle. Then we've got on the right
deep learning. So these are all algorithms that have
something to do with neural networks. Deep learning,
basically anything that's called the Deep learned Algren falls in
here. They don't have to be national language processing
. They could be classification. They could be anything
so they could be. That's deplorable. Here on
national language processing is any algorithm an immortal that has
something to do with President ofthe natural language into machine
terms. And then finally, in the overlap,
we have deep NLP. So these are models which
have to do with national language processing, but also
which are deep learning malls, neural network models on
DH? Yes. Oh, that's the part that
we're going to be aiming for. But it's also
very good to have visibility off all three, because
in this course we will be talking about some models
that fall just in here. And then we'll be
talking about most here, and I'll be good to
compare and see how the world has changed over time
and why these models are off for better than these
ones. Um, another thing to note here is
that the size of these diagrams is not reflective off
the importance or the volumes off thes different fields.
So I just said circles of the same size simply
because we want a visual representation of off the overlap
and that these fields exist. But don't take the
size into account. It's not to scale at all
. And finally there is another part. Another part
of this event diagram, which is very important to
us. And it is this part over here,
a sub section off a deep NLP cold sequence to
sequence. So sequence the sequence models on the most
cutting edge the most powerful models that exists right now
for national language processing. And that's what we're going
to be looking at. So as you'll see throughout
this course, you will make a way through the
national language processing side of things into deep NLP,
and then we'll go into sequence to sequence. It
will be a fun and exciting journey on DH.
The other thing that I wanted to mention is you
will also notice that throughout this course, even though
it's focused on chatbots, we won't be talking about
Just chat boards will be looking at different examples off
how these models from here from here and from here
can be applied to different things. Because the applications
are huge. We can talk. We can apply
them in a natural you neural mission. Translation.
We're gonna play them in image capture name. We
can apply them in speech recognition questions and answers.
Tex immunization. Lots of lots of models, so
we will be looking at different ones and they will
be up to protect. So this map will come
in handy as we go through the course and then
we'll be popping up here and there. So I
think it was very important for us to set the
foundation right, so that now we're age proceed.
And I can't wait to see you on the next
tutorial. And until then, enjoy deep a national
language processing.